Lisa's detail the rights of the parties
but sometimes limit the opportunity to
pursue civil claims
tenants sue their landlord for lying
about a stench and come up smelling like
roses in Italian Cowboy Partners versus
Prudential Insurance Company
Hudson's Grill leased commercial space
from Prudential Insurance Company during
Hudson's lease a sewage smell plagued
the space property manager Fran Powell
experienced the odor and called it
ungodly and gag inducing Hudson's
vacated the space
restaurateurs Francesco and Jane Seiki
operated Italian Cowboy the seikis
negotiated with Prudential through
Powell to lease the space
Powell told the seikis that the building
was almost new without problems and the
previous tenant didn't experience any
problems
the lease included a standard merger
clause and a clause that stated no
representations were made beyond the
lease under the lease Italian cowboy was
responsible for certain repairs but
Prudential needed to maintain sewer
lines and had authority over structural
alterations
the odor re-emerged and then worsened
when cleaners unclogged a pipe for the
grease trap the city temporarily closed
the restaurant following a report to the
health department the seikis and
Prudential unsuccessfully tried to
address the problem the seikis stopped
paying rent and closed Italian Cowboy
when they learned Powell withheld
information about Hudson's problems
a subsequent tenant learned the
improperly installed grease trap and
piping caused a sewage backup new piping
and relocating the kitchen resolved the
issue
Italian Cowboys sued its landlord and
property manager for rescission and
brought tort and contract claims
including fraudulent inducement and
breach of the implied warranty of
suitability Prudential counterclaimed
for breach of contract at trial the
court found for Italian Cowboy rescinded
the lease and awarded damages the
appeals court reversed Italian Cowboy
petitioned the Texas Supreme Court